<refentry id="glutForceJoystickFunc.3GLUT">
	<refmeta id="glutForceJoystickFunc.3GLUT-meta">
		<refentrytitle>glutForceJoystickFunc</refentrytitle>
		<manvolnum>3GLUT</manvolnum>
	</refmeta>
	<refnamediv id="glutForceJoystickFunc.3GLUT-name">
		<refname>glutForceJoystickFunc</refname>
		<refpurpose>forces current window's joystick callback to be called.</refpurpose>
	</refnamediv>
	<refsynopsisdiv id="glutForceJoystickFunc.3GLUT-c_spec">
		<title>C Specification</title>
		<funcsynopsis>
			<funcprototype>
				<funcdef>void&nbsp;<function>glutForceJoystickFunc</function></funcdef>
				<void/>
			</funcprototype>
		</funcsynopsis>
	</refsynopsisdiv>
	<refsect1 id="glutForceJoystickFunc.3GLUT-description">
		<title>Description</title>
		<para>
			<function>glutForceJoystickFunc</function> forces the current window's joystick callback to be called, reporting the
			latest joystick state.
		</para>
		<para>
			The joystick callback is called either due to polling of the joystick at the uniform timer interval set by <function
			moreinfo="refentry">glutJoystickFunc</function>'s <parameter>pollInterval</parameter> (specified in milliseconds) or in
			response to calling <function>glutForceJoystickFunc</function>. If the <parameter>pollInterval</parameter> is
			non-positive, no joystick polling is performed and the GLUT application must frequently (usually from an idle callback)
			call <function>glutForceJoystickFunc</function>.
		</para>
		<para>
			The joystick callback will be called once (if one exists) for each time <function>glutForceJoystickFunc</function> is
			called. The callback is called from <function moreinfo="refentry">glutJoystickFunc</function>. That is, when <function
			moreinfo="refentry">glutJoystickFunc</function> returns, the callback will have already happened.
		</para>
	</refsect1>
	<refsect1 id="glutForceJoystickFunc.3GLUT-glut_implementation_notes_for_x11">
		<title>Glut Implementation Notes For X11</title>
		<para>
			The current implementation of GLUT for X11 supports the joystick API, but not actual joystick input. A future
			implementation of GLUT for X11 may add joystick support.
		</para>
	</refsect1>
	<refsect1 id="glutForceJoystickFunc.3GLUT-glut_implementation_notes_for_win32">
		<title>Glut Implementation Notes For Win32</title>
		<para>
			The current implementation of GLUT for Win32 supports the joystick API and joystick input, but does so through the
			dated joySetCapture and joyGetPosEx Win32 Multimedia API. The current GLUT joystick support for Win32 has all the
			limitations of the Win32 Multimedia API joystick support. A future implementation of GLUT for Win32 may use
			DirectInput.
		</para>
	</refsect1>
	<refsect1 id="glutForceJoystickFunc.3GLUT-see_also">
		<title>See Also</title>
		<para>
			<simplelist type="inline">
				<member><citerefentry>
					<refentrytitle>glutJoystickFunc</refentrytitle>
					<manvolnum>3GLUT</manvolnum>
				</citerefentry></member>
			</simplelist>
		</para>
	</refsect1>
</refentry>
