<refentry id="glutFullScreen.3GLUT">
	<refmeta id="glutFullScreen.3GLUT-meta">
		<refentrytitle>glutFullScreen</refentrytitle>
		<manvolnum>3GLUT</manvolnum>
	</refmeta>
	<refnamediv id="glutFullScreen.3GLUT-name">
		<refname>glutFullScreen</refname>
		<refpurpose>requests that the current window be made full screen.</refpurpose>
	</refnamediv>
	<refsynopsisdiv id="glutFullScreen.3GLUT-c_spec">
		<title>C Specification</title>
		<funcsynopsis>
			<funcprototype>
				<funcdef>void&nbsp;<function>glutFullScreen</function></funcdef>
				<void/>
			</funcprototype>
		</funcsynopsis>
	</refsynopsisdiv>
	<refsect1 id="glutFullScreen.3GLUT-description">
		<title>Description</title>
		<para>
			<function>glutFullScreen</function> requests that the current window be made full screen. The exact semantics of what
			full screen means may vary by window system. The intent is to make the window as large as possible and disable any
			window decorations or borders added the window system. The window width and height are not guaranteed to be the same as
			the screen width and height, but that is the intent of making a window full screen.
		</para>
		<para>
			<function>glutFullScreen</function> is defined to work only on top-level windows.
		</para>
		<para>
			The <function>glutFullScreen</function> requests are not processed immediately. The request is executed after returning
			to the main event loop. This allows multiple <function moreinfo="refentry">glutReshapeWindow</function>, <function
			moreinfo="refentry">glutPositionWindow</function>, and <function>glutFullScreen</function> requests to the same window
			to be coalesced.
		</para>
		<para>
			Subsequent <function moreinfo="refentry">glutReshapeWindow</function> and <function
			moreinfo="refentry">glutPositionWindow</function> requests on the window will disable the full screen status of the
			window.
		</para>
	</refsect1>
	<refsect1 id="glutFullScreen.3GLUT-x_implementation_notes">
		<title>X Implementation Notes</title>
		<para>
			In the X implementation of GLUT, full screen is implemented by sizing and positioning the window to cover the entire
			screen and posting the _MOTIF_WM_HINTS property on the window requesting absolutely no decorations. Non-Motif window
			managers may not respond to _MOTIF_WM_HINTS.
		</para>
	</refsect1>
	<refsect1 id="glutFullScreen.3GLUT-see_also">
		<title>See Also</title>
		<para>
			<simplelist type="inline">
				<member><citerefentry>
					<refentrytitle>glutReshapeWindow</refentrytitle>
					<manvolnum>3GLUT</manvolnum>
				</citerefentry></member>
				<member><citerefentry>
					<refentrytitle>glutPositionWindow</refentrytitle>
					<manvolnum>3GLUT</manvolnum>
				</citerefentry></member>
			</simplelist>
		</para>
	</refsect1>
</refentry>
